Carmen Aguilar García

Date of birth: 15th November 1986 in Granada (Spain)

Telf.: +447713847043 <u>@C_Aguilargarcia</u> Mail: carmen.aguilar.garcia@gmail.com

More about me: https://carmen-aguilar.github.io/hello/

I have been working as a TV reporter and a multimedia journalist since 2009 in Spain and Chile. I am now based in the UK studying a MA in Data Journalism and developing skills in visualisation, coding, and analytical thinking.

WORKING EXPERIENCE



Sept 2014 – April 2017. 24HORAS.CL. Chile. Multimedia and TV journalist.

Member of the Innovation and Investigation Department. Live broadcasting. Awarded with prize: "Pobre el que no cambia de mirada", "Periodismo sustentable" and "Digital Excellence in Journalism*.



Jun 2015 - Nov 2015. L'INDRO. Chile. Correspondent.

Correspondent from Chile for the Italian international news magazine L'Indro, covering topics in depth.



May 2014 – Sept 2014. PULSO. Chile. Multimedia journalist.

Multimedia news in the Chilean financial newspaper. Awarded with prize: Sustainable Journalism**.

ESTRATEGIA

Dec 2013 – Mar 2014. ESTRATEGIA. Chile. **Journalist**.

Writing reports and news in the International Economy Department of the Chilean business newspaper.



Feb 2010 – Jan 2013. TELEMADRID. Spain. TV Reporter.

Coverage, writing, editing and broadcasting live in a wide variety of local and national current issues for the Spanish regional television.



Feb 2011 - Jun 2011. RADIO 12FM. Spain. Radio journalist.

Co-editor and co-announcer in the magazine "Conexión Doble Vía", for migrant community in Madrid.



March 2009 – Oct 2009. AGENCIA EFE. Spain. Journalist.

Coverage, writing and edition of the national current affairs in Madrid for the video department. Internship.



Jul 2008 – Aug 2008. CADENA SER. Spain. Journalist.

Coverage of the regional current affairs and writing task. Contributor to the radio magazine "Hoy por Hoy" and "Hora 14", both in Cadena SER Granada. Internship.

SKILLS AND COMPETENCES

Personal
SOCIAL: Responsible, creative, able to manage
stressing situations, easily adaptable in work-teams,
willing to new challenges, with initiative
LANGUAGES: Spanish (mother tongue), English
(CAE), Italian (CILS2), German (B2)
OTHER: Driving licence

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

- 2017-present Birmingham City University. MA Data Journalism.
 - Modules include narrative techniques, data visualisation and coding tools, data analysis, investigative and specialist reporting.
- 2014. Universidad Católica de Chile. Postgraduate Studies in Visual Executive Production *Modules include project management, budget administration and project development.*
- 2004-2009 Universidad Carlos III de Madrid. BA in Journalism and Visual Communication Modules include broadcast and print journalism, scientific, international and financial reporting, media regulation, video production and edition.
- 2007-2008 Università di Bologna. Erasmus Exchange Programme Modules include cinema history, video production and edition, visual ethic and semiotic.

AUDIOVISUAL PROJECTS

- Biographic **documentary** about the priest Jaime Garralda, *Salir del pozo* (Freelance)
- **Documentary** about press' freedom in Colombia, *Vuelo LP158: Destino la otra Colombia* (BA project)

ADITIONAL TRAINING

- Course: Digital tools for Data Journalism, in Knight Centre for Journalism in Americas
- Course: Data journalism, in LEARNO
- Course: Google Analytics Data Analysis
- Course: International cooperation, in Red Cross
- Course: Locutor to radio and television, in AM Studios

MORE DETAILS

- *Awards*
 - o Reconstrucción en Valparaíso: http://bit.ly/1sVwNWJ
 - o Cuánto dinero pierdes cuando tiras comida a la basura: http://bit.ly/1VN0Uwx
 - o Radiografía municipal de Chile: http://bit.ly/2AgePGc
 - o Nominee with Migrantes, los nuevos niños de Chile: http://bit.ly/1R1VWrD
- **Award: La rentabilidad del hogar sustentable: http://bit.ly/10msmZK
- Beneficiary from the X Edition of the First Employment Programme, awarded by the Press Association of Madrid
- Member of the Erasmus Student Network Association
- Available to travel and to move away